# **BREANNA COACH**

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

- Portfolio Site
- in linkedin.com/in/coachbre
- github.com/Coachbre
- coachbre.dev@gmail.com
- 865-622-1296

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JAVASCRIPT
- REACT
- HTML
- CSS
- JSON
- VS CODE
- MATERIAL UI

- GIT/GITHUB
- C.#
- SQL
- .NET
- MVC
- VISUAL STUDIO

### **PROJECTS**

## GENTLE-FICATION FRONT-END CAPSTONE

Gentle-Fication is an app that assists both existing and new residents of gentrified neighborhoods by gathering community events, resources, and city council information into one central site. My app is meant to provide residents with an easy way to track and participate in events that make sure all community members benefit from the positive effects of gentrification, as well as foster a sense of community.

- Single-page app utilizing React and JSON server API calls
- Full CRUD functionality
- Styling was achieved through CSS and Material UI
- Check out Gentle-Fication on github!

#### ABOUT ME

I am a former bank operations specialist pursuing a career that would present both a constant challenge, as well as constant rewards. The aspect of being able to create and problem-solve drew me to software development, and the ever-changing field standards keep me excited day by day!

### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

## Software Developer

Nashville Software School | February 2021- present

A full-time 6 month software development intensive, focusing on creating applications using full-stack technologies.

- Experience in remote collaboration
- Git and GitHub for version control
- Created ERDs to determine database dependencies
- Acquainted with an agile work environment through group collaboration and technical communication
- Utilized tools including Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, and Postman
- Creation of single page applications using a varied tech stack including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React
- Application production with a focus on server-side tech including C#, SQL and .NET

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Wire Operations Specialist

First Horizon Bank | 2017 - 2021

- Processed internal and external domestic wire transfer requests
- Collaborated with team members to correct wire errors
- Communicated changes in process with off-site team members
- Assisted with new employee training

## **Emergency Dispatcher/Customer Experience**

ADT Security | 2015 - 2017

- Dispatched authorities based on alarm type
- Assisted customers with equipment troubleshooting
- Handled account changes, billing inquiries, and maintenance requests



### **PROJECTS**

# HOLIDAY ROAD FRONT-END GROUP PROJECT

Holiday Road is a front-end group project with the task of creating a 'National Parks' travel itinerary app based on a chosen 'client persona'

My main contributions included writing the Javascript that handled populating the itinerary previews and detail snapshot/alert boxes to the DOM, as well as slight CSS relating to UI/UX.

- Team exercise focused on Javascript, creating ERDs, and JSON server API calls
- Styling was achieved through vanilla CSS
- Check out Holiday Road on github!

# TABLOID-FULL STACK BACK-END GROUP PROJECT

An online news platform where users can create/delete, comment on, classify, and add tags to articles. Implements full CRUD with a focus on authorization/authentication.

My assigned responsibility was writing all the code for the 'tag' section CRUD functionality.

- Team exercise using ASP.NET Core, MVC, C#, SQL, Javascript and CSS/ReactStrap
- Check out Tabloid on github!

## Sales Representative

Kings Beauty Supply 2014 - 2015

- Assisted customers with purchase decisions
- Educated customers based on their specific product needs
- Participated in product testing and guide training

#### **EDUCATION**

## Nashville Software School

|| Software Bootcamp Certificate
Six-month Full-Stack Web Development
Intensive

## Douglas J. Aveda

|| Cosmetology Certificate
Twelve-month Full-time Cosmetology
theory and licensure course

# Alcoa High School || H.S. Diploma

